Guide to the Davies/Scroggie Collection of Canadian Fur Trade Documents
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Comments imprint: [Montréal] De l'Imprimerie de Brown. "From archivalsources and private collections, we note a flurry of contracting activity during the month of December 1811 and running over into January 1812. This activity was undoubtedly provoked by the visit of William McGillivray to New York in January of 1811 and the resultant formation of the South West Fur Company in copartnership with John Jacob Astor. The outbreak of the War of 1812 in June of 1812 would have rendered much of this activity meaningless as most of the voyageurs would have by then been enlisted in the famous Canadian Corps of Voyageurs. In effect, this outfit, as well as the outfits of 1813 and 1814, would never be." (Lande, p. 80).
Lande type MF11
83.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Modeste Cornoyer (Cournoyer) of Maska
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position second steersman
Payment 300 livres, and additional 200 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Michel Danis
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 15 piastres; will receive another 6 when leaving
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
84.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Prisque (?) Cornoyer (Cournoyer) of Sorel
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position milieu
Payment 250 livres, and additional 150 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Prisque Cournoyer
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 10 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
85.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Michel Danis of Maska
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position milieu
Payment 250 livres, and additional 150 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Michel Danis
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive another 6 when leaving
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
86.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Louis Decoeure (?) of Rigaut (Rigaud)
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position steersman
Payment 400 livres, and additional 200 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Louis Decoeure
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 20 piastres; will receive another 8 when leaving
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
87.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Pierre Dorval of Sorel
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position steersman
Payment 400 livres, and additional 200 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Pierre Dorval
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 20 piastres; will receive 8 piastres when leaving
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
88.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Antoine Giguère of Yamaska
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position bowsman
Payment 400 livres, and additional 200 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Pétal Mandeville
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 30 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
89.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Joseph Hue (?) of Sorel
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Posts of the Northwest
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 600 livres for the first year, and the rates and conditions of the post for the others
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Joseph Hue
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 15 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown. Equipment is detailed as above.
Lande type MF11h
90.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Laurant (Laurent) Lambert of Maskinongé
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position steersman
Payment 400 livres, and additional 200 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Laurent Lambert
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 20 piastres; will receive another 8 when leaving
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
91.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Antoine Lesieur of Berthier
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Posts of the Northwest
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 600 livres for the first year, and the rates and conditions of the post for the others
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Antoine Lesieur
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 12 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown. Equipment is detailed as above.
Lande type MF11h
92.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Pétal [?] Mandeville of Sorel
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position bowsman
Payment 400 livres, and additional 200 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Pétal Mandeville
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 25 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
93.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Michel Peltier (Pelletier) of Sorel
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position milieu
Payment 250 livres, and additional 150 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Michel Pelletier
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 15 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
94.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Antoine Pierre of Lanoraie
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position milieu
Payment 250 livres, and additional 150 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Antoine Pierre
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 10 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
95.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Antoine Plante of Sorel
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position milieu
Payment 250 livres, and additional 150 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Antoine Plante
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 15 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
96.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur André Rocquebrune of Rivière à la Graisse
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position bowsman
Payment 400 livres, and additional 200 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of André Rocquebrune
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 30 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
97.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Jean-Baptiste Roy of Lanoraie
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position milieu
Payment 250 livres, and additional 150 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of Jean-Baptiste Roy
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 10 piastres
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
98.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur François Salois of Maska
Place & date Montréal, 30 December 1811
Destination Fort William
Position second steersman
Payment 300 livres, and additional 200 if he travels to Rainy Lake
Length of contract return trip
Signatures mark of François Salois
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 20 piastres; will receive another 8 when leaving
Comments imprint: De l'Imprimerie de Brown.
Lande type MF11
99.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Joseph La Noix (?) of St-Cuthbert
Place & date Montréal, 18 December 1820
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Joseph La Noix; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 10 piastres; will receive 6 when leaving
Comments "The dating of type MF20 is facilitated by the fact that thephrase 'l'an mil huit cent vingt___' is employed ... we judgethis form to have been printed in the fall of 1820. Note thatthe list of named empowered partners is now headed by Williamand Simon McGillivray. The next partner, Archibald Norman McLeod, had by this time become firmly installed, since the tragic death in 1816 of Kenneth Mackenzie, as the Montrealhiring agent of the NWC." (Lande, p. 88).
Lande type MF20h
100.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Augustin Bourdeau of LaPrairie
Place & date Montréal, 19 December 1820
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment the rates, conditions and equipment of the post where he will winter
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Augustin Bourdeau; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 16 piastres; will receive 16 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
101.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Antoine Archambeault (Archambault) of L'Assomption
Place & date Montréal, 9 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Antoine Archambault; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive 8 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
102.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Michel Gill of St-François
Place & date Montréal, 9 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment the rates, conditions and equipment of the post where he will winter
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Michel Gill; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 12 piastres; will receive 10 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
103.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Joachim Larivière of L'Assomption
Place & date Montréal, 9 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment the rates, conditions and equipment of the post where he will winter
Length of contract two years
Signatures mark of Joachim Larivière; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 20 piastres; will receive 10 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
104.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Joseph Larivière of L'Assomption
Place & date Montréal, 9 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Joseph Larivière; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive 10 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
105.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Baptiste Renaud of L'Assomption
Place & date Montréal, 9 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Baptiste Renaud; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive 6 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
106.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Jean-Marie Rocquebrune of Vaudreuil
Place & date Montréal, 9 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Jean-Marie Rocquebrune; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 20 piastres; will receive 10 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
107.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Godfroy (Godefroy) Boyer of Ile Perrot
Place & date Montréal, 10 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Godefroy Boyer; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive6 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
108.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur André Dubois of Vaudreuil
Place & date Montréal, 10 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of André Dubois; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive8 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
109.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Antoine Grégoire of St-Ours
Place & date Montréal, 10 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" steersman
Payment 1000 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Antoine Grégoire; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 20 piastres; will receive10 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
110.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Isidore Beauchamp of Montreal, tinsmith
Place & date Montréal, 20 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Isidore Beauchamp; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive 8 when leaving
Comments as above. It is interesting to note that no special mention is made in the contract of the voyageur to work in his trade; a tinsmith would be a highly valued addition to any fur trading post. It is also surprising he was not paid additional wages.
Lande type MF20h
111.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Louis Lafranchise of Faubourg St-Antoine (Montreal), blacksmith
Place & date Montréal, 20 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures signed by Louis Lafranchis [sic]; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 10 piastres; will receive 10 when leaving
Comments as above. A blacksmith would be even more appreciated in a trading post.
Lande type MF20h
112.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Joseph Toin (Thouin) of L'Achigan
Place & date Montréal, 22 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Joseph Thouin; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive 8 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
113.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Pierre Lord of Rivière-du-Loup
Place & date Montréal, 23 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu and labourer
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Pierre Lord; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres
Comments as above. Would the additional mention of labourer (a term that would apply to nearly all voyageurs) imply that he was required to perform more than the usual tasks at the posts? If so, this is not stipulated in the contract.
Lande type MF20h
114.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Joseph Jannot (Jeannot) of La Rivière à la Graisse
Place & date Montréal, 25 January 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Joseph Jeannot; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 8 piastres; will receive 8 when leaving
Comments as above for regular wintering contracts.
Lande type MF20h
115.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Paul Vallé (Vallée) of Ste-Anne
Place & date Montréal, 26 February 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" bowsman
Payment 1200 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Paul Vallée; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 20 piastres; will receive 10 when leaving
Comments as above.
Lande type MF20h
116.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Antoine Allard St-François
Place & date Montréal, 12 March 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" steersman
Payment 1200 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Antoine Allard; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 100 piastres; will receive 50 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
117.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Xavier Melouez (?) Of Faubourg des Recollets (Montreal)
Place & date Montréal, 12 April 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures mark of Xavier Melouez; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur receives an advance of 12 piastres; will receive 12 when leaving
Comments as above
Lande type MF20h
118.
Outfitter Archibald Norman McLeod, partner, for M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays& Co.
Voyageur Louis Chevrette of St-Cuthbert
Place & date Montréal, 9 May 1821
Destination Posts of the Northwest in Upper Canada
Position "wintering" milieu
Payment 700 livres per annum
Length of contract three years
Signatures marks of Louis Chevrette and Jos. Baudry; signed by A.N. MacLeod
Observations the voyageur recognizes having received an advance of 215 livres; will receive 8 when leaving
Comments as above. In this contract Chevrette takes the place of Joseph Baudry, who was hired in December 1819, obviously didnot do the voyage, and whose contract is hereby cancelled.
Lande type MF20h
119.
Outfitter Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co.
Voyageur Antoine Denyeau (Daignault) of St. Phillippe
Place & date Montreal, 30 April 1802
Destination Michilimackinac and Southern (U.S.) Posts
Position milieu
Payment 650 livres
Length of contract one year
Signatures mark of Antoine Denyeau
Observations received double the usual equipment and 50 livres on account
Comments This contract is for the XY Company
Lande type GN02(h)
120.
Outfitter Pierre de Rocheblave
Voyageur François Richard of Faubourg St. Laurent
Place & date Montreal, 8 January 1817
Destination Michilimackinac, obliged to continue to Sault Ste-Marieand, if so requested, around the lakes
Position steersman
Payment 250 livres
Length of contract return trip, without wintering
Signatures notary Beek (contemporary notarial copy)
Observations received 10 piastres on account and will receive another12 piastres when leaving
Comments Pierre de Rastel de Rocheblave, 1764-1840, fur traderfounding member of the XY Company. Rocheblave was given responsibility for the Voyageurs' Fund along with ThomasThain. (The Voyageur Fund was the earliest pension fund inCanada).
Lande type GN17
Contract labor -- Canada; Fur trade -- Canada; Fur trade -- North America; Fur traders -- Canada; Fur traders -- United States; Trading posts -- Canada; Trading posts -- North America; Fort Michilimackinac (Mackinaw City, Mich.); Thunder Bay (Ont.); Grand Portage (Minn.); Rainy Lake (Minn. and Ont.); Contracts -- Canada -- 19th century; Davies, Carole-Ann Scroggie, 1949-; Davies, Grant, 1947-; McLeod, Archibald Norman; American Fur Company; M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co; M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays & Co
- 1999 Acquisition, 1801-1821
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by outfitter.
  Scope and Contents
  The 1999 Acquisition consists of 120 voyageur contracts (1801-1821). For complete listing and description, see the Appendix.
  - American Fur Co. (four items), 1818; 4 (Box 1)
  - David Mitchell, Jr., 1806 (Box 1)
  - Forsyth, Richardson & Co., 1806 (Box 1)
  - Joseph Faniant, 1803 (Box 1)
  - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. (42 items), 1801-1806; 42 (Box 1)
  - M'Tavish, McGillvrays & Co. (68 items), 1808-1821; 68 (Box 1)
  - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co., 1802 (Box 1)
  - Pierre de Rocheblave, 1817 (Box 1)
- December 2001 Acquisitions, 1751-1822
  Organized under three headings: Voyageur Contracts, Documents concerning the bankruptcy of the North West Company, and Canadian Fur Trade Documents.
  The December 2001 Acquisitions consist of 17 voyageur contracts (1802-1821), 36 documents relating to the Canadian fur trade (1751-1822), and six documents relating to the bankruptcy of the North West Company (1826-1828).
  - Voyageur Contracts
    Not arranged in any particular order.
    Voyageur contracts are listed by the name of outfitter.
    General note
    Former call number: Uncat MSS 259
    - Forsyth, Richardson & Co. (2 items), 1806; 2 (Box 2)
    - Parker, Gerrard, Ogilvy & Co. (2 items), 1802; 2 (Box 2)
    - American Fur Co. (5 items), 1818 March 16; 5 (Box 2)
    - M'Tavish, Frobisher & Co. (5 items), 1801 -1811; 5 (Box 2)
    - M'Tavish, M'Gillivrays & Co. (3 items), 1820 -1821; 3 (Box 2)
  - Canadian Fur Trade Documents
    Former call number: Uncat MSS 260
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Blondeau, Maurice. Promissory note to Charles Nolan Lamarque, 1751 July 27 (Box 2)
    - Lamarque, Charles Nolan. Receipt to François Le Fevre, 1752 February 25 (Box 2)
    - Lupien dit Baron, Joseph. Obligation to Pierre Bouthillier & Patterson, 1766 August 20 (Box 2)
    - Howard, Joseph. Statement of account with the estate of Claude-Nicolas de Lorimier de La Rivière, 1773 August 31 (Box 2)
    - Mener & Ramsay. Autograph letter, signed, to William Taylor, 1775 September 4 (Box 2)
    - Finlay, James & Co. Protested note drawn by Toussaint Pothier, 1775 September 10 (Box 2)
    - Williams, Thomas. Autograph letter, signed, to Alexander Hay, 1781 August 17 (Box 2)
    - Williams, Thomas. Autograph letter, signed, to William Dummer Powell, 1781 October 12 (Box 2)
    - Heward & McCaslan. Autograph letter, signed, to William Dummer Powell, 1783 September 23 (Box 2)
    - Auldjo, John. Power of attorney, 1784 April 2 (Box 2)
    - Barclay, J. & R. Copies of letters to William Taylor (two items), 1785 January (Box 2)